ROBERTO MORTERA

Lic. en Animación y Arte Digital Tecnológico de Monterrey



CONTACT DETAILS

- Querétaro, México
- □ robmrtra@gmail.com
- S +52 442 2309928
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/roberto-mortera/

PROFILE

I have 5 years of experience working on 3D animation projects, both for movies and TV shows.

I have the talent to work in small and large teams, as well as leadership, good organization and responsibility. I easily adapt to different work environments and I am someone who carefully analyzes the instructions given to provide a better result in the project in which I am required. I am always willing to learn from others as well as offer my help and share my knowledge. Open to new experiences and opportunities.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

3D Animator at Boxel Studios, Tijuana, Baja California Norte, México

MAY 2023 - PRESENT

Working remotely as a freelance 3D animator on two confidential projects.

3D Animator at Exodo Animation Studios, Guadalajara, México

JULY 2023 - AUGUST 2023

Worked remotely as a 3D animator.

3D Animator at Insert Coin Animation Studio, Colombia

NOVEMBER 2022 - MAY 2023

Worked remotely as a 3D animator on some music videos from the YouTube channel "Cocomelon".

3D Animator at Mighty Animation, Guadalajara, Jalisco, México

APRIL 2021 - NOVEMBER 2022

Worked remotely as a 3D animator on the animated TV shows "Friends Z Space" and "100% Wolf".

3D Animator at Zebra Studio, Ciudad de México, México

SEPTEMBER 2020 - DECEMBER 2020

Worked remotely as a 3D animator on the animated Christmas parade "Bolo Fest 2020".

3D Animation Artist, Technicolor Academy, Montréal, Québec, Canada

SEPTEMBER 2019 - APRIL 2020

I was part of the Technicolor Academy program and collaborated as a roto-animator in some shots of the movie CATS 2019.

3D Animator and Crowds Animator at Huevocartoon, Querétaro, Querétaro, México

APRIL 2018 - AUGUST 2019

Worked as a 3D animator on the movies "Un Rescate de Huevitos" (2021) and "Huevitos Congelados" (2022)

EDUCATION

Bachelor's Degree in Animation and Digital Art, Tecnológico de Monterrey, Campus Querétaro, México AUGUST 2011 - MAY 2016

3D Animation and Body Mechanics, Coco School, Alicante, España SEPTEMBER 2016 - JULY 2017

COURSES AND CERTIFICATIONS

The Complete JavaScript Course 2023, Udemy JULY 2023 - PRESENT

Build Responsive Real-World Websites with HTML and CSS, Udemy JANUARY 2023 - MAY 2023

Full Stack Web Delevopment, Academio OCTOBER 2022 - APRIL 2023

3D Animation Workshop, Intermediate and Advanced, Animsquad DECEMBER 2018 - MARCH 2019

SKILLS

Autodesk Maya - Advanced HTML - Intermediate CSS - Intermediate Photoshop - Intermediate After Effects - Intermediate

LANGUAGES

Spanish - native language English - written and spoken